Guide to the Marcel Kurpershoek papers AD.MC.054
New York University Abu Dhabi Library
- Printed material: copied books and texts in Arabic and English
  - Ḥaqīl, Ḥamad Ibrahim al. [Saudi judiciary]. Abdulaziz in History: history and \ literature (Abdulaziz fii al Ta'arikh). Ta'arikh wa…Beirut, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Ibrahim ibn Ṣāliḥ ibn ʿῙsā. 'Iqd al-durar fī mā waqaʿ fī Nājd min al ḥawādith. [String of pearls about what happened in Najd at end of 13th century AH and the 14th century]. Damascus [relates to earlier title], 1953 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Khuwayṭir, ʿAbdulaziz al. History of Osman ibn Bisha, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - al Kunun as-Sha'biyah [Popular treasury] (1), 1961 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - al Kunun as-Sha'biyah [Popular treasury] (2), 1961 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - al Kunun as-Sha'biyah [Popular treasury] (3), 1961 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - al Kunun as-Sha'biyah [Popular treasury] (4), 1961 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Lerick, Alison [sp?]. Stories from the 'Taghrīb' of Banu Hilal wars of al-Daylan. Governor of Riyadh province, (Salman bin Abdulaziz). Intro by Abdullah bin Mohamed bin al-Hamis. Princeton (doct diss?), 1984 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Lewin, Bernard. Book of Plants of Abu Ḥanīfah ad-Dīnawarī [re: Arabic names of plants] [suggested discard by PMK], 1952 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Mazini, Ibrahim Abdulkader al. Voyage to al Hejaz [Rihlah al Hejaz]. (printed by Fuad, in Cairo, n.d., pre wWII) (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Part 2: Bedouins of the Sinai (begins at p. 239). (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Muʿjam asmā' al-nabātāt [dictionary of names of plants] from "Tāj al-ʿĀrūs" [names of plants excerpted from larger dictionary]. Cairo, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Rayhānī. Amīn al. Ta'rīkh Najd wa-mulḥaqātih. [Life story of King Abdulaziz, King of Hejaz and Nejd and its dependencies] Beirut, self-printed (Dar al Rayhan), 1927 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Rubay'an, Fahd al Mohamed al. al-'Uraynāt. Vol. 1 (AH 1398). (relates to Subay'an tribal history) (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Safrani, Ali al Hamad al. Diwān anbar al afqar., v. 1 (The Lights of Sa'd] [Nabati poetry] AH 1377 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Safrani, Ali al Hamad al. Vol. 3. Min al-bādiyah [from the Bedouins/desert] AH 1377 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Samerai, Amer Rashid al. Researches into popular literature (Baghdad, 1964). Ministry of Culture…. [mabakhesth il ettabashabi] (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Siba'i. Ahmed al. Ta'rikh Mekka, v.1. (Mecca, AH 1380) (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Siba'i. Ahmed al. Ta'rikh Mekka, v. 2. (Mecca, AH 1380) (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Thumayri, Mohamed ibn Ahmed al. Al funun al sha'biyyah fii al jazirat al Arabiya [Popular arts in the Arabian Peninsula], 1973 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - 'Ubayyid, Abdulrahman al Kareem al. Qabīlat al-'Awāzim [Al Awazim tribe: Study about its origins, its social structure, and its lands. Riyadh, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - 'Uqaylan, Ahmed Farad al. Jināyat al-shiʿr al-ḥurr [The crime of free poetry]. Literary Club of Abhah, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Wahba, Hafez. Jazīrat al-ʿArab fī al qarn al-ʿishrīn: Peninsula of the Arabs in the 20th century. [standard work but hard to get]. Cairo, 1946 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Ẓāhirī, Abdulrahman ibn 'Aqil al. āl al-Jarba' fī l-ta'rīkh w-al-adab. [re sheikhs of Shammar tribe in Nejd and Syria], 1983 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Zāmil, Abdullah al Ali al Mansūr al. Aṣdaq al-bunūd fī ta'rīkh Abdulaziz al Saud [Most truthful records of the history of Abdulaziz al Saud]. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - al Arab [journal]. [article on Saudi history/literature]. Ed. Hamad, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - [to be identified] (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Abu Athera, Said Salman. Love and mockery: …Bedouin poetry from Jordan and Sinai (abstract, undated, Oxford) (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Abu Athera, Said Salman. Tribal poetry of the Tarabin and Huwaytat tribes (1) (doctoral dissertation, University of Glasgow, 1995) (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Abu Athera, Said Salman. Tribal poetry of the Tarabin and Huwaytat tribes (2) (doctoral dissertation, University of Glasgow, 1995) (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Ageili, al-, Mahmoud S. The settlement of the nomadic tribes in the Northern Province: Saudi Arabia (doctoral dissertation, University of Manchester, 1986) (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Boot, J.W.A. The tribe in the modern Arabian Peninsula: Abu Dhabi, a case study. (graduation essay, University of Leiden, 1995) (Box 20, Folder 5)
- Photographs and miscellaneous
  General
  Materials currently in process.
- Filmed footage (Middle East News / al Arabiya television), 2017